Guide to the Alpha Phi Omega, Alpha Xi Records 1935-1972
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Alpha Phi Omega, Alpha Xi Records
1935-1972
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 406
Alpha Phi Omega, Alpha Xi Chapter
1 container. 1 linear feet of shelf space.
Correspondence, charters, constitutions, financial records, membership lists and applications, and other papers of a service fraternity at Washington State University.
Alpha Phi Omega fraternity was founded nationally in 1925. According to its charter the organization "seeks to develop Leadership, and promote Friendship and provide Service," in accordance with the code of the Boy Scouts of America. Alpha Xi, the W.S.U. chapter of this honorary service fraternity, was established in 1935.
Included in the records are correspondence, the charter and constitution, receipts, membership lists, pledge ship applications, ephemera, bulletins, and other papers. Although the records span dates from 1935 to 1972, the bulk of the material dates from 1962 to 1968.
The records of the Alpha Xi Chapter of the Alpha Phi Omega are arranged in a single series, alphabetically by topic.
This collection is open for research use.
The records of Alpha Xi Chapter of Alpha Phi Omega were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by the organization through Arthur E. McCartan and Leonard Young on May 4, 1978 (UA 78-11).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Alpha Phi Omega. Alpha Chapter --Archives
Greek letter societies--Washington (State)--Pullman--Records and correspondence
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Active Applications Sent to National Office, 1962-1966; 55 items. (Box-folder 1 / 1)
- Active Members, 1966; 21 items. (Box-folder 1 / 2)
- Administration Manual, 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 3)
- Alpha Phi Omega (APO), 1967-1968; 21 items. (Box-folder 1 / 4)
- APO Phone Lists, February 1969; 9 items. (Box-folder 1 / 5)
- APO Services, 1968; 36 items. (Box-folder 1 / 6)
- Application Blanks, 1963-1967; 15 items. (Box-folder 1 / 7)
- Application Blanks-Membership, 1957-1959; 65 items. (Box-folder 1 / 8)
- Applications for Pledgeship, 1956; 50 items. (Box-folder 1 / 9)
- Banquet, February 1, 1968; 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 10)
- Bylaws and Association Articles, 1968; 6 items. (Box-folder 1 / 11)
- Chapter Doings, 1965-1966; 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 12)
- Chapter Membership Records, 1967-1968; 38 items. (Box-folder 1 / 13)
- Computer Readout, 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 14)
- Correspondence, 1959-1971; 15 items. (Box-folder 1 / 15-16)
- CUB (receipts), 1963-1966; 22 items. (Box-folder 1 / 17)
- Daily Attendance Chart, 1 item. (Box-folder 1 / 18)
- Ephemera, December 1, 1964; 13 items. (Box-folder 1 / 19)
- Initiated Members Applications, 1949-1952; 6 items. (Box-folder 1 / 20)
- Handsome Harry--Sweet Sue, 1960-1968; 84 items. (Box-folder 1 / 21-24)
- Leadership Directory, 1963-1968; 10 items. (Box-folder 1 / 25)
- Life Membership Application Blank, 1 item. (Box-folder 1 / 26)
- Members, 1935-1969; 265 items. (Box-folder 1 / 27-28)
- Membership List, 1951-1968; 10 items. (Box-folder 1 / 29)
- Membership Transfer Application Blank, 1 item. (Box-folder 1 / 30)
- Minutes, 1968-1971; 35 items. (Box-folder 1 / 31)
- Miscellaneous (receipts, bulletins), 1963-1965; 27 items. (Box-folder 1 / 32)
- National Convention, 1965-1970; 72 items. (Box-folder 1 / 33-37)
- National Convention Bulletin, December 27-29, 1970; 8 items. (Box-folder 1 / 38)
- National Office, 1969; 41 items. (Box-folder 1 / 39)
- Notes: Past, 1964; 11 items. (Box-folder 1 / 40)
- Notes: For School Year, 1964; 7 items. (Box-folder 1 / 41)
- Official Order Blank, 1 item. (Box-folder 1 / 42)
- Northwest Sectional Conference Delegates' Photograph, November 23, 1968; 1 item. (Box-folder 1 / 43)
- Pledges, 1966-1978; 9 items. (Box-folder 1 / 44)
- Pledge Applications, 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 45)
- Pledge Applications Sent to National Office, 1962-1966; 58 items. (Box-folder 1 / 46)
- Projects: New Business, 1 item. (Box-folder 1 / 47)
- Projects: Past Records, 1966-1967; 14 items. (Box-folder 1 / 48)
- Projects To Do, 1966-1968; 8 items. (Box-folder 1 / 49)
- Receipts, 1962-1968; 21 items. (Box-folder 1 / 50-51)
- Receipts: WSU, 1963-1965; 43 items. (Box-folder 1 / 52)
- Ritual Manuals, 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 53)
- Sectional Conference Data, 1964-1965; 6 items. (Box-folder 1 / 54)
- Sectional Material, 1968; 32 items. (Box-folder 1 / 55)
- Song Sheets, 10 items. (Box-folder 1 / 56)
- Sponsor's Constitution, 2 items. (Box-folder 1 / 57)
- Task Forces, 1970-1972; 4 items. (Box-folder 1 / 58)
- Tax Forms, 1951-1965; 17 items. (Box-folder 1 / 59)
- Training Aids: New Membership Lists, 1968-1970; 40 items. (Box-folder 1 / 60)